World War I and II Era Media Collection 1913-1995 (bulk 1914, 1940-1945, 1994-1995)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
World War I and II Era Media Collection 1913-1995 (bulk 1914, 1940-1945, 1994-1995)
MS 577
University of Arizona. Library. Special Collections.
Collection of newspapers and magazines related to the United States in World War I, World War II, World War I era popular culture and other military related topics.
4 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series.
Series I: World War I Era and Popular Culture, 1913-1914
Series II: World War II, 1940-1950
Series III: Other military related, 1959, 1973
Scope and Content Note
Collection of newspapers and magazines related to the United States in World War I, World War II and other military related topics. Popular culture materials include clippings from media of pictorial images and printed matter. The magazines include Look and Life, and the newspapers include the New York Times Book Review and New York Times Magazine from the 1940s. Large collection of front page war stories from 1945 and remembrances of D-Day from the 1990s. Artificial collection with donations from Gary Opper [bulk] and unknown, donated circa 2005 and 2015
Access Terms
World War, 1914-1918 – Press Coverage.
World War, 1939-1945 – Press Coverage.
World War, 1914-1918 – United States.
World War, 1914-1918 – Social aspects.
World War, 1939-1945 – United States.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Pictorial works..
World War, 1939-1945 – Personal narratives.
Container List
- World War I Era and Popular Culture, 1913-1914; Series 1
  - Newspapers and clippings including The New York Times, McCall’s, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- World War II, 1940-1950; Series 2
  - Look, Life and Fortune magazines, oversize, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New York Times Magazine, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - World War II articles, D-Day remembrances, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Other military related, 1959, 1973; Series 3
  - Newspapers, 1959, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)